[MUSIC]
[음악]
There are many ways to shop for products today.
오늘날 상품 구입 채널은 아주 다양합니다
Typically though, you have to use what's called keyword search.
일반적으로 키워드 검색이란 걸 사용하죠
You type a query on a search engine and
검색 엔진에 검색어를 입력해서
try to find products that are interesting to you.
관심 상품을 찾습니다
But let's look at new ways to shop.
새로운 방법을 알아보죠
So for example, let's say I want to buy a shoe, or buy a pair of shoes.
신발 한 켤레 살 때를 볼게요
Now some people just really care about shoes, I really care about shoes.
어떤 사람들은 신발에 꽤 신경을 많이 쓰죠 저도 그런 편입니다
I have, let's say, this cool black pair of shoes.
저에게 멋진 검은 구두 한 켤레가 있는데
It's got some real style to it.
스타일이 살아있습니다
I have this other black pair of shoes.
다른 검은 구두 한 켤레가 있는데
It might look to you as most the same, but
거의 비슷해 보이지만
they're totally different, totally different styles.
실제로는 완전히 다른 스타일이죠
I have this crazy dress shoe.
아주 괜찮은 드레스 슈즈도 있는데요
They might look transparent to you, but it's actually a really cool shade of blue.
별거 아닌 거처럼 보이지만 사실 약간 파란색을 띠는데 좋습니다
I have this crazy, two-colored sneakers, which I love.
이 투톤 운동화는 제가 무척 아낍니다
I also have this other really interesting pair of sneakers,
여기 이건 홍콩에서 산 꽤
which I bought in Hong Kong, and they're kind of fun.
재밌는 운동화입니다
And everybody knows I like purple, so I even have this purple boots.
저 보라색 좋아하는 건 아시죠 보라색 부츠도 있습니다
>> Forget it, you have a lot of shoes.
>> 그만 해요 신발 많은 건 알겠어
>> I have a lot of shoes, but I need more shoes.
신발이 많은데 더 필요합니다
And so, there's a lot of shoes online.
온라인에 신발 종류가 많죠
And it's really hard to find the ones that are interesting, stylish, different,
그중 관심 가는 거 찾기가 어렵죠 스타일리시하고, 색다르고,
kind of like my style.
제 스타일인 신발요
And if I use keyword search, it doesn't really help me.
키워드 검색으로 찾아도 되지만 별 도움은 안 됩니다
If I have to type the dress shoes, I just find a bunch of boring usual shoes.
드레스 슈즈를 입력하면 하품 나오는 평범한 구두만 나오죠
Although the ones on the top left-hand corner,
오른쪽 위에 있는 건 그나마 특이하고
they're kind of interesting and stylish.
스타일리시하지만요
But still, I want to find something different, and
색다른 걸 찾을 때 어떤 키워드를 입력할지
I don't know what keywords to type or how to search for it.
어떻게 찾아야 하는지 모르겠습니다
So, what should I do?
어떻게 해야 할까요?
Let me start by showing you a cool demo of a new way to shop based on
유사도 기반의 새로운
similarity search.
쇼핑 데모를 보여드리죠
Let's talk about something even more complicated than buying shoes.
신발보다 복잡한 걸 이야기해보죠
My sister is a fashion designer and her birthday's coming up.
패션 디자이너인 여동생이 있는데 생일이 다가옵니다
And I want to buy her a really interesting,
꽤 그럴듯한 걸 하나 사주려고 해요
cool gift that she might love.
동생이 좋아할만한 거요
Well maybe I wanna buy her a dress.
드레스를 사주려고 합니다
So if I just use textual keyword search and I try to look for
본문 키워드 검색으로 드레스를 찾으면
a dress, I'm gonna find a bunch of dresses.
여러 개가 나옵니다
But I really don't know how to choose a dress that she'll like
그러나 이 속성만으로 동생이 좋아할 드레스가 어떤 건지
just based on these properties here.
알기 어렵습니다
And I don't know how to describe it.
일단 표현을 어떻게 해야 할지 모릅니다
How do you describe the dress my sister might like?
동생이 좋아할 드레스를 뭐라고 표현하죠?
Now, I could say maybe she loves floral dresses.
꽃무늬 드레스를 좋아한다고 하죠
Even if I say floral dresses, I'm still presented with a number of options
그렇다고 해도 꽃무늬 드레스 종류가
in different kinds of floral dresses, and her style is pretty unique.
한두 가지가 아니고 동생 스타일도 독특합니다
So how am I gonna find a dress that really looks like something she will love?
동생이 좋아할만한 드레스를 어떻게 찾을까요?
So if I scroll down this list, maybe I'll see something that catches my eye.
목록에서 내려보면 눈에 띄는 게 있습니다
Oh here's a floral dress that looks pretty good, so I'm gonna click on that.
이 꽃무늬 드레스가 아주 좋아보이네요 클릭해보죠
And instead of just finding dresses based on keyword search,
키워드 검색에 의존하기보다
I wanna use image similarity to find similar dresses.
이미지 유사도를 통해 비슷한 드레스를 찾습니다
So this are dresses that look similar to this one, just based on image qualities.
이미지 특성에 따르면 이것들이 여기 이 드레스와 비슷하게 보입니다
And you see that now we get dresses that do have similar properties.
비슷한 특성의 드레스가 나온 게 보이시죠?
And now, this is much easier to to kind of find something that she might like.
이제 동생이 좋아할만한 걸 찾는 게 훨씬 쉬워졌습니다
But of course, many of these dresses are a little too usual.
물론 대부분은 너무 평범합니다
And she might want something a little bit more interesting.
좀 더 특이한 걸 원할 거 같군요
So for example, here's one which has multiple patterns.
예를 들어 여기 이것에는 여러 무늬가 있죠
And now we find dresses that are similar.
그리고 비슷한 드레스를 찾습니다
And you see they have multiple styles within a dress.
각 드레스마다 여러 스타일이 공존하고 있죠
How will I know how to describe that?
이걸 표현하자면 어떻게 될까요?
So let me search within the set.
이중에서 검색해보죠
And say, oh, you know what, this one looks pretty good.
그리곤 오 이건 꽤 괜찮아 보이네요
And if I click on that, you see other visually similar dresses to this one,
클릭하면 시각적으로 유사한 드레스가 나오고
but this one looks particularly good.
이게 그중 나아보입니다
And the more I looks a little bit like my sister too, so perfect gift for her.
모델도 동생이랑 어느정도 닮았네요 완벽한 선물이 될 거 같습니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]